topic yeah all right I hope that I hope
是的，没事，我希望我希望
I didn't speak with on mute all right
我没跟静音说话
I hope I'm also not speaking on mutes
我希望我也不要讲静音
it's any way for me to find out okay
我可以通过任何方式找出
okay I'm fine all right thanks so
好吧，我很好，谢谢
welcome everyone um I guess I'm not
欢迎大家，我想我不是
gonna have to do the present present
要做现在的礼物
myself ports now I'm Eric and I'm gonna
我自己搬家，现在我是Eric，我要
talk about concurrent class loading and
讨论并发类加载和
before we get into it I have to provide
在我们开始之前，我必须提供
this fun safety harbor statement that
这个有趣的安全港声明
basically says you can't trust anything
基本上说你什么都不信任
I say but fortunately is all open source
我说，但是幸运的是所有开源
if you have doubts you can always go and
如果您有疑问，可以随时去
check out the code see if it's really do
查看代码，看看它是否确实在做
what I'm saying so the agenda for today
我要说的是今天的议程
is the following first we're gonna talk
接下来是我们要谈的第一件事
about well what is the DC what is class
关于什么是DC什么是类
unloading and get an overview over the
卸载并获得概述
different phases involved and I'm gonna
涉及不同的阶段，我要
deep dive a little bit into code cache
深入研究代码缓存
and loading and metadata unloading and
以及加载和元数据卸载以及
eventually get into some kind of
最终陷入某种
evaluation and future plans right so
评估和未来计划正确
what is the GC it is a new concurrent
什么是GC这是一个新的并发
garbage collector introduced in JDK 11
JDK 11中引入的垃圾收集器
and it's currently an experimental
这是一个实验性的
feature and it works only on x86 64
功能，仅适用于x86 64
Linux at the moment but we're looking
目前使用Linux，但我们正在寻找
into expanding the platform support and
扩展平台支持
to get a better understanding about that
对此有更好的了解
you see it's best to look at the goals
你看到最好看一下目标
we have with the project and as for now
我们有这个项目，到目前为止
the ad goals are to scale and when I
广告目标是按比例缩放以及何时
talk about scale I mean we want to be
谈论规模，我是说我们想成为
able to run a multi-time byte heaps and
能够运行多次字节堆，并且
still maintain maximum DC safe or exist
仍然保持最大的DC安全或存在
pastimes of in 10 milliseconds
10毫秒内的消遣
for this we are willing to pay a limit
为此，我们愿意支付一定的限额
in throughput but not more than 15%
吞吐量不超过15％
throughput reduction another goal that
减少吞吐量的另一个目标是
we take very seriously is we want it to
我们非常重视我们想要它
be as easy as possible to tune we don't
尽可能容易地调整我们不
want a hundred JVM flags that nobody
想要一百个没有人的JVM标志
knows what they're doing we wanted to
知道他们在做什么，我们想
work well out of the box as much as
开箱即用
possible and I find that it helps to
可能，我发现它有助于
make everything concurrent to achieve
使所有事情并发实现
that right so I said it's the concurrent
没错，所以我说这是并发的
garbage collector well what do I mean by
垃圾收集器好，我的意思是
that g1 is a concurrent garbage
g1是并发垃圾
collector let's look into some details
收藏家让我们看一些细节
of different operations the garbage
不同操作的垃圾
collector has to perform for example we
收藏家必须执行例如
have to mark all the objects in the heap
必须标记堆中的所有对象
traverse the heap and and mark all the
遍历堆并标记所有
objects and we have to perform
对象，我们必须执行
compaction we have to defragment memory
压缩我们必须整理内存碎片
and clear up large contiguous memory
并清理大的连续内存
spaces so we can have urban pointer
空间，所以我们可以有城市指针
allocations we also need to perform
我们还需要执行的分配
reference processing and we need to have
参考处理，我们需要
relocation set selection to figure out
重定位集选择以找出
where is the best bang for the buck to
最好的地方在哪里
perform compaction and we need to do a
执行压缩，我们需要做一个
whole bunch of other stuff like string
一大堆其他东西，例如字符串
in string table cleaning and global ref
在字符串表清洗和全局引用中
scanning and most notably class
扫描，尤其是班级
unloading we need to do class unloading
卸载我们需要做类卸载
and we also need to scan thread thread
而且我们还需要扫描线程
stacks so if you look at the notorious
堆栈，所以如果您看臭名昭著的
nor most of the world collectors like
世界上大多数收藏家都不喜欢
serial GC and peril GC surprise surprise
串行GC和风险GC令人惊讶
everything is done in a safe point and
一切都在安全的点完成，
that's how it works and if we look at
这就是它的工作方式，如果我们看一下
CMS in g1 marking is concurrent and when
g1标记中的CMS是并发的，何时
I say marking it's specifically the
我说标记它是专门
strong references in the old generation
在上一代人中有很强的参考
that are traversed concurrently the rest
其余部分同时遍历
such as expanding finalized errs and the
例如扩大最终错误和
transitive closure was reachable from
传递闭包从
them as well as young generation is done
他们以及年轻一代已经完成
in a safe point and with said GC we're
在一个安全的点上，有了GC，我们
checking all the green boxes except
检查所有绿色框，除了
thread stack scanning haven't worked
线程堆栈扫描无效
that one out yet but the rest is
那一个出来了，剩下的就是
current and I've highlighted class
目前，我已突出显示课程
unloading here in bulk because that was
在这里大量卸载，因为那是
the the last safe want operation to bite
最后一次安全的抢劫行动
the dust it's now I'm done concurrently
现在已经尘埃落定
and nobody else is doing now right so we
现在没有人在做，所以我们
release concurrent class unloading for
释放并发类的卸载
12 I'm talking the past tense as if this
12我说的是过去时
has already happened 12 is an out yet
已经发生了12次了
but it will be in 12 it's basically
但基本上是十二点
checked into 12 and it's on its release
签入12并在发布中
train and the the the traditional phases
训练与传统阶段
we have to go through to perform class
我们必须经过上课
unloading on the following can split it
在下面卸载可以将其拆分
up into first some kind of marking we
首先是我们的标记
have to mark objects and when they mark
必须标记对象以及何时标记
the armies will also mark the metadata
军队还将标记元数据
reachable from these objects so that we
可从这些物体到达
know what's live and eventually need to
知道生活是什么，最终需要
perform reference processing during
在执行参考处理
reference processing typically you would
参考处理通常会
expand what's reachable from finalize
从完成中扩展可达到的范围
errs which is an additional set of
错误，这是另外一个
marking that's usually done in a safe
标记通常是安全的
point and eventually you'll get to the
点，最终您将到达
unloading part which is where we walk
我们走的地方是卸货部分
all the dead data structures and get rid
所有失效的数据结构并摆脱
of all all the all the dead data so this
所有所有无效数据中，所以这
is both the code cache and the meta data
既是代码缓存又是元数据
that needs to be purged with the GC we
需要使用GC清除
are doing more things concurrently so it
正在同时做更多的事情，所以它
looks quite similar but not quite
看起来很相似但不太完全
notably during marking when we marking
特别是在标记过程中
metadata and and objects we are marking
我们正在标记的元数据和对象
both what's reachable from the strong
两者都是强者可以达到的
references and the obvious are reachable
引用和显而易见的都是可以达到的
through finalized errs so that when our
通过最终的错误，以便当我们
marking terminates we need know the
标记终止，我们需要知道
aliveness of both final reachable
最终的生命力
objects and strongly reachable objects
对象和高度可达的对象
so that the subsequent reference
以便后续参考
processing is simplified in the sense
在某种意义上简化了处理
that it will never it will net change
它将永远不会改变
changed aliveness it's already been
改变了生命力
computing during the concurrent marking
并发标记期间的计算
and that allows us to continue doing
这样我们就可以继续
concurrent class
并发类
loading as well and there again we will
以及加载，我们将再次
walk the code cache we walked a minute
走了我们一分钟的代码缓存
data and purged out all the stuff that
数据并清除所有
is dead
死了
so the faces for zgc looks something
所以zgc的脸看起来有些东西
like this the large downward facing
像这样的大面朝下
arrows or safe point operations we have
箭头或安全点操作
three of them in a cycle the first one
其中三个周期中的第一个
is the mark start a safe point and there
商标是一个安全的起点吗？
we basically walk the stacks and kick
我们基本上是走堆然后踢
off the concurrent traversal that is
并发遍历是
running well the job application is
运行良好的工作应用程序是
running and eventually we terminate the
运行，最终我们终止了
marking in mark end and after that
在标记末端和之后标记
that's when things the lightness
那就是事物的轻盈
information is complete we know stuff
信息是完整的，我们知道
has died and we start another concurrent
已经死了，我们开始另一个并发
face and during this concurrent phase
在这个并发阶段
this is where we do concurrent reference
这是我们进行并发引用的地方
processing and concurrent class
处理和并发类
unloading eventually we get to a
最终我们卸载到
concurrent relocation face but we have a
并发搬迁面孔，但我们有一个
safe one before that where we flip a bit
安全的一点，在那之前，我们稍微翻转一下
in a global global mask and then we
在全球的全球范围内，然后我们
start running and we basically evaluate
开始运行，我们基本上进行评估
a whole heap and perform relocation
整个堆并执行重定位
concurrently so the first step let's
同时进行，所以第一步
look a little bit deeper in that marking
在该标记中看起来更深一点
so we have colored pointers and that
所以我们有彩色的指针
means that the GC phases are tied to a
表示GC阶段与
specific color of the pointers and when
指针的具体颜色以及何时
we marking things were peculiar color
我们标记的东西是奇特的颜色
that we want the pointers to have to
我们希望指针必须
mark them as strongly reachable we also
将它们标记为高度可达，我们也
have a particular color for things
有一种特殊的颜色
reachable through finalized errs so the
通过最终的错误可以到达，因此
final reachable objects the pointers
最终可达对象的指针
have a specific color that is detected
具有检测到的特定颜色
in our load bars
在我们的负载条中
so in our load barriers we can promote
因此，在我们的负载障碍中，我们可以促进
final reachable objects to becoming
最终成为的对象
strongly reachable and this works in a
高度可达，这在一个
similar fashion for metadata as well
元数据也是如此
that the metadata can be reachable
元数据可以访问
through finalizes or
通过完成或
strongly and we need to keep track of
强烈，我们需要跟踪
which one of them it is so that we can
是其中之一，以便我们可以
do all magic concurrency stuff and if we
做所有魔术并发的事情，如果我们
look at what's hiding beneath the
看看什么藏在
objects the metadata it looks something
对象看起来像元数据的对象
like this
像这样
so we have a bunch of objects and you
所以我们有一堆东西，你
can have a direct link from it a Java
可以从它直接链接Java
object to a class loader that will keep
反对将保持的类加载器
it alive but um this is in the case here
它还活着，但是在这种情况下
we have a class pointer in the header
我们在标题中有一个类指针
word of each object and this class we
每个对象和这个类的词
have to mark as well so when we're
也必须标记，以便当我们
traversing through our objects we also
遍历对象
traversing through the class and well
遍历全班
the class has some reference to collect
全班有一些参考资料
its class loaded data and the class
它的类加载数据和该类
loader data has a bunch of handles in a
加载程序数据中包含一堆句柄
in a handle area that eventually point
在最终指向的手柄区域
out the class loader and some mirror
退出类加载器和一些镜像
classes and stuff like that so by
诸如此类的东西
marking the class we have to keep all of
标记课程，我们必须保留所有
this stuff alive basically but if
这些东西基本上还活着，但是如果
nobody's there is we haven't found any
没有人在那里，我们还没有找到
objects with a class that is that we
类的对象是我们
have marked and we haven't had obvious
已经标记，我们还没有明显
pointing our class letters and we can
指向我们的班级字母，我们可以
get rid of everything and we'll do that
摆脱一切，我们会做到的
so the next step is reference processing
所以下一步就是参考处理
this there's quite a lot to this I'm
这个我有很多
going to dumb it down as much as
会尽量哑巴
possible for for the simplicity of this
为了简单起见
presentation so basically have it the
演示，所以基本上有它
main point is that we have two different
要点是我们有两个不同
types of week references the normal
星期类型参考正常
normal week reference it gets cleared if
正常的一周参考，如果
the reference is not strongly reachable
参考不是很容易获得
but it can still be reachable through
但仍然可以通过以下方式访问
finalize they don't get clear
最后确定他们不清楚
nevertheless and the phantom references
但是，幻象引用
on the other hand they get cleared when
另一方面，当它们被清除时
the reference is simply not reachable at
在以下位置根本无法获得参考
all even through finalized errs and why
甚至通过最后的错误，为什么
is this important well it's important to
这重要吗
us because the VM weak references we
我们，因为VM弱引用了我们
have including the holders - - or class
包括持有人--或班级
loaded data that keeps the classes alive
加载的数据使类保持活动状态
it's the it has phantom reach ability so
它具有幻影达到能力，所以
have to be able to lazily compute the
必须能够懒惰地计算
readability of this stuff which we can
这些东西的可读性，我们可以
and we do and if the holder of the class
而我们这样做，如果班级的持有人
loaded data is know through a phantom
通过幻像知道加载的数据
axes then basically it's dead unless
轴然后基本上是死的，除非
there's there's some silly reference
有一些愚蠢的参考
counter as well but that's a whole
柜台也是，但这是一个整体
different kind of worms eventually get
最终会得到不同种类的蠕虫
to downloading part which is the fun
下载有趣的部分
stuff
东西
so after reference processing there's a
因此在参考处理之后
whole bunch of different data structures
一大堆不同的数据结构
that are now stale and contain contain
现在已经过时并包含
dead stuff yeah there's a subclass
死的东西，是的，有一个子类
hierarchy is with the sub links sibling
层次结构与子链接同级
and implementer lists there's some
实施者列出了一些
metadata data objects for profiling data
用于分析数据的元数据对象
we have instant class dependency context
我们有即时类依赖上下文
used for the optimization java.lang
用于优化java.lang
invoke call signs also have some
调用呼号也有一些
dependency context that also is used for
依赖关系上下文也用于
the optimization there's a class over
优化结束了
data graph we have a whole bunch of
数据图，我们有一堆
tables we have so many tables the
桌子我们有很多桌子
protection domain cache table module
保护域缓存表模块
table string table package table symbols
表字符串表包表符号
and there's a lot of tables they all
他们都有很多桌子
have that stuff now and yeah the list of
现在有这些东西，是的清单
tables just goes on and eventually we
桌子继续下去，最终我们
also have meta space which is kind of
也有元空间
important that we have a bunch of
重要的是我们有一堆
classes methods etc they all need to be
类方法等，它们都需要
get nuked we have a code cache in the
变得裸体，我们在其中有一个代码缓存
code cache we have just-in-time compiled
我们及时编译的代码缓存
code this code partially because has
将此代码部分编码是因为
dead stuff in it because the object
死了的东西，因为对象
references there have been inline into
引用内联到
the code or pointing to random crap in
代码或指向随机废话
the heap there is no longer live and in
堆里不再住了
addition we have inline caches for
另外我们有内联缓存
optimizing method calls
优化方法调用
they're also pointing at things are now
他们也指着现在的事物
dead because the object references died
死亡，因为对象引用死亡
and yeah that it the best way of
是的，这是最好的方式
describing this situation is the
描述这种情况是
following everything is a huge mess
跟随一切都是一团糟
but we just continue running anyway just
但是我们还是继续运行
look at that Jukka and the motorcycle
看看那辆Jukka和摩托车
he's absolutely crazy
他绝对疯了
right so we want some kind of structure
对，所以我们想要某种结构
to this madness and we made a
为了这种疯狂，我们做了一个
disciplined split between unlinking and
解除链接与链接之间的纪律性划分
purchasing so during class unloading we
购买，因此在上课时我们
split everything in an intern linking
将所有内容拆分为实习链接
and purging and it's separated by a
和清除，并用
thread local handshake operation with
与线程本地握手操作
all of these threads and the importance
所有这些线程和重要性
of this is that we want to make sure
这是我们要确保
that we have no racy accesses to these
我们没有民主的途径
links that we are unlinking well when we
链接，当我们断开链接时，
get to deleting it so when we purge the
删除它，以便当我们清除
data and start deleting stuff we don't
数据并开始删除我们不喜欢的东西
want anyone to be touching this stuff
希望任何人都可以触摸这个东西
because we will blow up so that's what
因为我们会炸毁，所以
we've done it that way so this goes for
我们已经做到了，所以
metadata unlink handshake purge and it
元数据取消链接握手清除及其
goes for the code cache as well a link
用于代码缓存以及链接
handshake purge that's the key right so
握手清除是关键，所以
let's talk a little bit more about the
让我们多谈一点
code cache and loading is this the most
代码缓存和加载是最重要的
fun stuff in my opinion so I think I
我认为有趣的东西，所以我想我
need to explain a little bit the two
需要解释一下这两个
main problems we have here one is that
我们这里的主要问题之一是
since we have colored pointers we have
因为我们有彩色的指针
this invariant that all the pointers
这个不变的所有指针
when we're running have the same same
当我们跑步时有相同的
same color but when we get to mark start
相同的颜色，但是当我们标记开始时
we start marking we haven't started
我们开始标记我们还没有开始
marking the object graph yet we need to
标记对象图，但我们需要
assign some kind of color right to the
将某种颜色分配给
immediate values have been in line into
立即值符合
the native code that we just in time
我们及时的本机代码
compile what color is that going to be
编译那将是什么颜色
well we can't we have to mark the as
好吧，我们不必标记为
marked because that's the face we're in
被标记，因为那是我们所在的面孔
but if we do that we have to also
但是如果这样做，我们还必须
actually mark the objects and if we're
实际标记对象，如果我们
marking the objects and we have a memory
标记对象，我们有一个记忆
leak because we can't unload stuff so
泄漏，因为我们无法卸载东西
how are we going to deal with that we'll
我们将如何处理
somehow we need to defer applying the
我们需要以某种方式推迟应用
load barriers to the the the object
向对象加载障碍
references in the native code somehow
以某种方式在本机代码中引用
not gonna spoil yet
还不会变质
how that's done we also have inline
如何做到的，我们也有内联
caches they are also very problematic
缓存也很成问题
because the inline caches compiled into
因为内联缓存被编译成
the native code have a cached quick
本机代码具有快速缓存
access to wherever they think that I
访问他们认为我存在的任何地方
call is going to go and it might know
通话将进行，它可能知道
now point at dead machine code we don't
现在指向死机代码，我们不
really want to take that call because
真的很想接那个电话，因为
we'll blow up so we need some kind of
我们会炸毁，所以我们需要某种
way there of stopping or preventing
停止或预防的方式
calls into this machine code with
调用此机器代码
absolutely explosive stuff in it how
绝对爆炸性的东西如何
we're gonna do that well the key to that
我们要做好那件事的关键
is end method entry barriers and these
是最终方法的进入障碍，而这些
entry barriers basically have a way of
进入壁垒基本上有一种方法
arming all the native code in the code
武装代码中的所有本机代码
cache except what we have on the stack
缓存，除了栈上的东西
because I wouldn't make any sense and
因为我没有任何意义
trap the next call into that native code
将下一个调用捕获到该本地代码中
and in in that little trap we get a call
在那个小陷阱里，我们接到了电话
every trampoline into the VM and in
每个蹦床都进入虚拟机
there we can figure out what to do about
在那里我们可以弄清楚该怎么办
this possibly stale native code that
这个可能过时的本机代码
we've jumped into and if what we do then
我们已经进入了，如果我们要做的话
is that we traverse the object
是我们遍历对象
references in the native code to see is
在本机代码中看到的引用是
this thing dead or not because that
这个东西死了还是没有，因为
matters to us if it is dead then we will
对我们来说很重要，如果它已经死了，那么我们将
do mais and basically get back into the
做mais，基本上回到
trampoline and call a method handle or a
蹦床并调用方法句柄或
method miss Handler and in that handler
方法Handler和该处理器中的方法
we will resolve the call to something
我们将解决呼叫问题
that makes more sense and redo the call
更有意义并重做通话
into interpreter whatever we end up in
无论我们最终进入翻译
that makes sense and for m-n methods
这是有意义的，对于mn方法
that are good that they have all the
很好，他们拥有所有
orbit references are alive it might
轨道参考可能还活着
still be that they have the wrong color
仍然是他们的颜色错误
and it might be that they need
可能是他们需要
relocation or remapping because they
迁移或重新映射，因为它们
have some stale pointer value
具有一些过时的指针值
and what we do then is to remap and
然后我们要做的是重新映射
paint on the right collar that we wanted
在我们想要的右衣领上绘画
to have by patching the machine code and
通过修补机器代码来拥有
eventually we disarm the barrier by
最终我们通过解除武装
again patching some more machine code to
再次修补一些机器代码
we patch the immediate value in the
我们在
compare instruction and assign it the
比较指令并为其分配
global correct value and that way when
全局正确值，当
we start running again
我们再次开始跑步
everything will make sense so I have
一切都会有意义，所以我有
some examples here
这里有一些例子
I think first example is calling into
我认为第一个例子是
dead code what could possibly go wrong
死代码可能会出错
so assume that we are in native method a
所以假设我们在本机方法中
and we have this inline cache with a red
我们有一个红色的内联缓存
red arrow going down to this potentially
红色箭头可能会下降
explosive native method B and we call
爆炸性的本地方法B，我们称之为
that well then what we're gonna do is we
那好吧，我们要做的是
walking the ambient references here and
在这里浏览环境参考和
find out that oh this is really bad
找出哦，这真的很糟糕
this guy is dead we should not be
这个家伙死了，我们不应该
calling this this code and then we re
调用此代码，然后我们重新
resolved the call and patch into the
解决了呼叫并将其修补到
inline cache in the machine code a jump
内联缓存在机器代码中跳转
to in this example a compiler to
在这个例子中
interpreter adapter that will allow us
解释器适配器将使我们
to take the execution over to the
将执行移交给
interpreter and it will all make sense
解释器，这一切都说得通
and we might compile new code and stuff
我们可能会编译新的代码和东西
like that next example is calling into
就像下一个例子
something that isn't dead so in this
没死的东西在这
similar scenario we are in native method
我们在本机方法中的类似情况
a we're calling native method B and once
我们正在调用本机方法B
we entered that we calling our little
我们进入，我们称我们的小
Barry function and there we walk tubes
Barry功能，我们在那里走管
and we find that okay well it looks like
我们发现好吧，看起来像
the Army references here are alive but
陆军的参考文献还活着，但
they're a little bit out of sync with
他们有点不同步
reality so no problem we patched him up
现实，所以没问题，我们修补了他
patch to machine code and disarmed the
修补机器码并撤防
barrier and we're good to go and
障碍，我们很乐意去
sequent calls into this method through
通过此方法的后续调用
that inline cache will we'll get there
内联缓存，我们将到达那里
without calling that barrier right so
没有称这个障碍为正确
from from the GC perspective we had
从GC的角度来看，
these two distinctive faces that we
这两个独特的面孔，我们
talked about a linked handshake perch
谈到一个链接式握手鲈鱼
and yeah during the unlinking the
是的，在取消链接期间
concurrently running garbage collection
同时运行垃圾回收
thread it will clean all the stale
线程将清除所有陈旧的
inline caches by patching the machine
通过修补计算机来内联缓存
code and it will resolve some it has a
代码，它将解决一些问题
year resolve handler that will patch
将解决的年度解析处理程序
this into the machine code so that it
这进入机器代码，以便
will resolve the call instead of calling
将解决呼叫而不是呼叫
this really bad code and we fix up
这个非常糟糕的代码，我们修复了
Toby's references also concurrently by
托比（Toby）也同时引用
the GC thread running and we also disarm
GC线程正在运行，我们也撤防了
the the barriers that the GC thread
GC线程的障碍
comes across and we also unlink
遇到，我们也取消链接
dependency contexts and this is a bit of
依赖上下文，这有点
a lock free dance going on where yeah
在那儿进行无锁舞蹈
the GC thread is unlinking this while
GC线程正在取消链接
the Java threads are potentially
Java线程是潜在的
mutating it as well but it all makes
也将其变异，但这一切都会使
sense I hate promise and similar story
感觉我讨厌诺言和类似的故事
for exception caches that there's a bit
对于异常缓存，有一点
of lock free code therefore unlinking
无锁代码，因此取消链接
exception caches while we're running
运行时异常缓存